indiawaterportal.org 2019-07-16

# Privacy Policy

**INTRODUCTION**

The purpose of this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is to describe how Arghyam, (“Arghyam”, “us”, “we” or “our” or “IWP”) collects, uses and maintains Information (as defined hereinafter) about the Users of its Portal and the Contributors of the User Content (collectively referred as “you” or “your”) on the Portal. All capitalised terms used in this Privacy Policy but not defined herein shall have the same meaning as ascribed to them in the Terms of Use available at <https://www.indiawaterportal.org/static-page/terms-use>. 

We recognize the importance of your privacy and are committed to ensuring that you are aware of how your Information is being used. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. Your use of the Portal is also governed by our Terms of Use.

If you do not understand any aspects of our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at [**contact@indiawaterportal.org**](mailto:contact@indiawaterportal.org). Please use and access the Portal only if you agree with our policies and practices encapsulated in this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. Your use or access of the Portal shall constitute your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**APPLICABILITY OF THE POLICY**

This Privacy Policy shall apply to all Information, IWP collects about the Users and Contributors. The Privacy Policy does not apply to, nor does IWP take any responsibility for, any information that is collected by any third party using the Portal.

**NATURE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED AND MANNER OF COLLECTION**

As you navigate through the Portal, IWP may collect different types of information, collectively hereinafter referred to as “Information”. This Information could be of the following types:

(i)“Sensitive Personal Information” - information such as your password;   

(ii)“Personally Identifiable Information” - information that could be used to identify you such as your name, email address, age, gender and other similar information including any User Information; 

(iii)“Non-Personal Information” - information that cannot be used to identify you including but not limited to cookies; 

(iv)“Device Information”- information which is automatically collected about the operating system or version of the system from which the Portal is used.

IWP may also collect information about the searches that you have carried out on the Portal or third-party links that you have visited, any emails or other correspondence you may have sent or exchanged with other Users or Contributors on the Portal or with IWP. 

You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of any Information you submit to IWP. Inaccurate Information may affect your ability to use the Portal, the Information you receive when using the Portal, and our ability to contact you. 

You understand that the Information collected by IWP, may be collected directly or through automatic tracking of your usage of the Portal through the use of cookies or other tracking technologies. The data automatically collected may include usage information such as details of your computing and/or communication device, location, connections, or any information that IWP may collect through the use of cookies and other tracking technologies. You may decline these cookies by changing your browser settings, if permitted. However, do note that this may impact certain features of the Portal or your experience in using the Portal.

You also may provide Information to be published or displayed or posted on the Portal or transmitted to other Users or other Contributors of the Portal or third parties. Any such Information that is posted or transmitted to other parties will be at your own risk and will not be monitored by IWP for its content or compliance. Please be aware that IWP cannot control the actions of other Users and Contributors of the Portal with whom you may choose to share Information with. 

**USE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

The Information that we collect on the Portal will be used for the following purposes:

(i)Correspondence/communication with you pursuant to your use as a User/ Contributor or your usage of the Portal;

(ii)Verification of your User or Contributor account, if applicable;

(iii)Ensuring that the content from the Portal is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device;

(iv)To provide you with newsletters, information, products or Services that you request from us which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;

(v)To notify you about changes to the Portal, this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use;

(vi)For the purpose of studying User and/or Contributor usage patterns;

(vii)For analytical purposes, including but not limited to assessing usage data, usage patterns, estimate audience sizes and other similar activities;

(viii)In any other manner as we may describe when you provide the Information.

Except as otherwise provided herein, no Sensitive Personal Information or Personally Identifiable Information will be published, disclosed or shared with any third party without your express consent. 

Please do not include or submit any Sensitive Personal Information or Personally Identifiable Information unless specifically requested by IWP as part of registering a User/Contributor account or pursuant to other applicable processes. If IWP determines that any Information you have provided or uploaded violates the terms of this Privacy Policy, IWP has the right, in its absolute discretion, to delete or destroy such Information without incurring any liability to you.  

Please note that by using the Portal you acknowledge and agree to the use of Google Analytics Advertising Features on the Portal by IWP and consequently you acknowledge and agree to the collection and processing of certain Information, provided by you, by Google. To know more about how Google collects and processes the data it collects from the Portal please visit [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), or any other URL Google may provide from time to time. In order to know how to opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Feature please visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. 

You agree to your Personally Identifiable Information being used by us in order to contact you and deliver information or administrative notices and any other communication relevant to your use of the Portal. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you may at any time inform IWP using the e-mail address: [contact@indiawaterportal.org](mailto:contact@indiawaterportal.org).

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We consider the confidentiality and security of your Information to be of the utmost importance. We will use industry standard physical, technical and administrative security measures to keep your Information including the Sensitive Personal Information and the Personally Identifiable Information, confidential and secure and will not share it with third parties, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, or unless we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary in special cases, such as in compliance with legal/ regulatory requests, to address, fraud, security or technical issues or a physical threat to you or other Users or Contributors. By providing any Information on the Portal, you consent to IWP providing such Information to any governmental, law enforcement or regulatory authorities who exercise jurisdiction over IWP and the Portal, upon receiving an order to do so under applicable law. 

IWP cannot guarantee the security of such Information because the Internet is not a 100% secure environment and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to circumvent our security systems or that transmission of your Information over the Internet will be intercepted. 

We may disclose your Information to our agents, employees, advisors and affiliates who require the Information for the purposes of operating and maintaining the Portal and for facilitating your use of the Services offered on the Portal. 

**DATA RETENTION**

IWP may retain Information, for such length of time as may be required in order for IWP to provide the concerned User or the Contributor  with Services, comply with legal obligations, resolve any disputes that may arise, enforce its rights arising out of agreements with Users or the Contributors, and/or for such period as may be required by legislations/orders of regulatory authorities to which IWP is subject.

**PRIVACY RIGHTS**

You acknowledge that the Portal is intended for use in the territory of India and that the Portal is operated and managed on servers that may be located and operated in or outside the territory of India. By using and accessing the Portal, you consent to the transfer to and processing of your Information including the Sensitive Personal Information and the Personally Identifiable Information, on servers that may be located in or outside the territory of India in accordance with applicable laws. If you chose to avail the Services or use of the Portal anywhere outside India, you shall choose to do so at your own risk and you acknowledge that you shall be solely responsible for any compliance with applicable laws in the jurisdiction from which you use the Services or the Portal

**DATA SECURITY**

The Information that you provide, subject to disclosure in accordance with this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, shall be maintained in a safe and secure manner. IWP’s databases and Information are stored on secure servers with appropriate firewalls owned by IWP or by third parties.

As an User or Contributor of the Portal you have the responsibility to ensure data security including that of your User Information. You should use the Portal in a responsible manner and you will not take any action that will cause a breach of the use of the Portal. You are solely responsible for all acts done using your User Information.

Given the nature of internet transactions, IWP does not take any responsibility for the transmission of Information including the Information you provide to the Portal. Any transmission of your Information on the internet is done at your risk. IWP does not take any responsibility for you or any third party circumventing the privacy settings or security measures contained on the Portal.

While IWP will use all reasonable efforts to ensure that your Information is safe and secure, it offers no representation, warranties or other assurances that the security measures are adequate, safe, fool proof or impenetrable. 

**ACCESSING AND UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION**

You may change, alter or otherwise modify or update your Information, at any time by contacting us at [contact@indiawaterportal.org](mailto:contact@indiawaterportal.org).

Do note however, IWP reserves the rights to save any Non -Personal, Device Information and usage information and you are not entitled to seek the deletion of the same.

IWP at its sole discretion may permit or deny the change of any Information, if it is believed the same is required to observe applicable laws. 

**AGE RESTRICTIONS**

The IWP is only intended for Users and Contributors who are competent to contract under applicable law. If you are not of the requisite age, you are not to provide any Personally Identifiable Information or Sensitive Personal Information or use the Portal or the Services. If it comes to IWP’s attention that any such information pertains to an individual who is not competent to contract under applicable law, such Information may be deleted without notice to you. In the event any User Content needs to be made available to a minor or someone who is not competent to contract or to someone who is not of applicable age, such User Content should be made available through a User who is competent to contract and who is of applicable age.

**COMPLAINTS  **

If you wish to place a complaint or raise a question/ concern with regard to your privacy requirements, or otherwise view, modify, delete or correct any of your Personally Identifiable Information or Sensitive Personal Information, please contact our Grievance Redressal Officer Mr. Suresh L. Ponappa at [contact@indiawaterportal.org](mailto:contact@indiawaterportal.org), or at contact number 080-46918941/42 so that we can consider and respond to your request/complaint. We shall endeavour to address all requests/complaints within thirty (30) days from the date of such a request/complaint being made.

**AMENDMENTS TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy is subject to change at IWP’s sole discretion. Any changes to the Privacy Policy will be notified by a notice on the home page of the Portal [https://www.indiawaterportal.org](https://www.indiawaterportal.org/).
